<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on </title>
    <link>/tags/Google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 07:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/Google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Opinion] Google Hiring Android Developers And The Android Ecosystem</title>
      <link>/post/opinion-google-hiring-android-developers-and-the-android-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 07:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/opinion-google-hiring-android-developers-and-the-android-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the Wall Street Journal ran a story about Google planning to hire Android application developers which, to me, seems to have the potential to be the worst possible thing they could do to the Android eco-system. I&amp;rsquo;m going to outline the reasons why I hold this view but I&amp;rsquo;m always open to other, well reasoned, points of view.
The reasons I currently have this view are as follows;
1. It does nothing to help non-Google developers who are currently struggling to make a living from developing Android applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android screen densities; what you see may not be what you get.</title>
      <link>/post/android-screen-densities-what-you-see-may-not-be-what-you-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 18:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/android-screen-densities-what-you-see-may-not-be-what-you-get/</guid>
      <description>Since Android 1.6 Google have beenasking developers to use specific size and density groupings for their graphical resources to ensure that their user interfaces looked good on a range of devices, but unfortunately developers are not fully supporting it and now OEMs are making their devices report the wrong densities.
I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged before about developers not supporting the various sizes and densities fully which resulted in UIs which look odd and empty on tablets, but OEMs reporting the wrong densities seems to be a new phenomenon which means even if a developer provided graphic assets for all the screen sizes and densities Android supports they may still see the wrong assets being used and their UI looking odd on some devices through no fault of their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, Android, and Private APIs.</title>
      <link>/post/google-android-apps-and-private-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 07:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-android-apps-and-private-apis/</guid>
      <description>[Declaration of interest: My company runs AndAppStore, an alternative to Googles Android Market]
Theres been a fair amount of talk around Googles use of &amp;ldquo;Private APIs&amp;rdquo; in their Android applications since the Andy Rubin interview which appeared in the NY Times Bits blog, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out what appears to be a glaring mistake in one of the replies Andy gave.
During the interview he said;
I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether he said this because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about what&amp;rsquo;s in some of Googles Android applications, or whether he was towing a party line about Androids&#39; open source nature, but that statement simply isn&amp;rsquo;t true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marking Apps on Googles Android Market</title>
      <link>/post/marking-on-the-googles-android-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 07:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/marking-on-the-googles-android-market/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be a lot of variation on how many stars people give an application on Googles Android Market. Some give 3 stars for an app they find hard to use, others give 1 star because the developer chose not to make the applications source code available (even though this doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the application as delivered to the user).
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stick to the following marking scheme and would welcome comments and feedback as to any changes people think would make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Market for Android Paid Apps launch = Fail</title>
      <link>/post/google-market-for-android-paid-apps-launch-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-market-for-android-paid-apps-launch-fail/</guid>
      <description>Android developers have been waiting for the ability to list pay-for applications in Googles Market, but now most of them wish it had never arrived because the experience it&amp;rsquo;s giving users may just turn them off Android forever.
The first joy is the &amp;ldquo;copy protection&amp;rdquo; offered by Google. Developers can turn this on for their apps but doing so can stop a the application running at all regardless of if it&amp;rsquo;s been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will the Android Market T&amp;Cs kill off &#34;fun&#34; apps?</title>
      <link>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</guid>
      <description>Over recent weeks there has been a lot of speculation over when Android users will be able to buy applications from Googles Market, but some of the terms and conditions in the Developer Distribution Agreement could scare many developers away before they deploy their first application.
The first thing that came to light is that purchasers will have 24 hours in which they can get a refund apparently with no questions asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will US Patent laws strange Android?</title>
      <link>/post/will-us-patent-laws-strange-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 10:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/will-us-patent-laws-strange-android/</guid>
      <description>In recent days there the issue of the US patent obtained by Apple relating to the multi-touch functionality has reared it&amp;rsquo;s head on the Android development lists, and the discussions have left me deeply concerned about whether Android will ever become a serious global player in the mobile OS market.
The discussion started rolling when a patch to add multi-touch functionality on Android was posted on the android-platform mailing list, and ran in parallel another list directly discussing the impact the patent may have, but surprisingly ended up with a post from a Google employee saying that patents should not be discussed on any of the google hosted android lists, and this was further expanded by another Google employee saying that it was &amp;ldquo;because of legal repercussions&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;it is simply best not to know about them&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Googles Android may have already failed</title>
      <link>/post/where-googles-android-may-have-already-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 10:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/where-googles-android-may-have-already-failed/</guid>
      <description>(Declaration of interest; I&amp;rsquo;m involved in AndAppStore.com which allows Android Applications developers to list Android applications and users to download them)
Imagine this; You have a product you want to make available worldwide, but you need the help of others to make it popular. You start a worldwide PR campaign, you make a mock-up available so people become familiar with your product, you run a worldwide competition for people to come up with uses for your product, and then you announce launch dates in one country for one date, another for a month later, a few more next year, and, well everyone else, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see what happens.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
