<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on </title>
    <link>/categories/Conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 12:15:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/Conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Droidcon London 2013</title>
      <link>/post/droidcon-london-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/droidcon-london-2013/</guid>
      <description>I got a call from Skills Matter asking me if I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in going to droidcon London 2013&amp;hellip;. well, it&amp;rsquo;s already certain I&amp;rsquo;ll be there, and here&amp;rsquo;s why;
There are going to be several tracks at #DroidconUK13 , and each track has a track-master, a person who has volunteered to co-ordinate the track, sort out who talks in which slots, and make sure their track is appealing to developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I/O 13 or Droidcon</title>
      <link>/post/io-13-or-droidcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 09:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/io-13-or-droidcon/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s been confirmed; #io13 will be yet another free-for-all with the freebie grabbers :(
This means I&amp;rsquo;m now definitely going to give it a skip it in favour of Droidcon Berlin and droidcon London later in the year. Whilst I&amp;rsquo;ve had some good conversations at #io events I&amp;rsquo;ve also had a number of ones which left me thinking &amp;ldquo;OK, this person isn&amp;rsquo;t really into coding and technology&amp;rdquo;, whereas at the Droidcons I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the only time I&amp;rsquo;ve thought that was talking to some of the people who have stands and are clearly identifiable as sales people (usually wearing a company T-shirt or something similar).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I/O Freebies</title>
      <link>/post/io-freebies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 08:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/io-freebies/</guid>
      <description>So now people are expecting a Chromebook Pixel and an X-Phone as giveaways at #io13 . If it&amp;rsquo;s open ticket sales again this year I can see the developer attendee count going down and the freebie hunter count going up.
At #io12 I met a guy who guy who said he was getting two of everything because he bought a ticket for himself and one for his son. His son was at college studying English, had no interest in the freebies, but took up the offer of a free trip to San Francisco in return for turning up to pick-up the goodies at the times his Dad told him to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk on Android Tablets</title>
      <link>/post/talk-on-android-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 10:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/talk-on-android-tablets/</guid>
      <description>At the end of October I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk on Android Tablets, eReaders, and other devices at droidcon London, so if you&amp;rsquo;ve found my posts on the subject interesting (or if you want to see any of the other speakers who are going to be presenting), the you can register to attend the Droidcon UK website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
