<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paypalx on </title>
    <link>/tags/paypalx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paypalx on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 08:36:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/paypalx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PayPal X Contest Winners - Good &amp; Very Bad.</title>
      <link>/post/paypal-x-contest-winners-good-very-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 08:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/paypal-x-contest-winners-good-very-bad/</guid>
      <description>First off the good. AppBackr. They came second, and as far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware they didn&amp;rsquo;t break any rules. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally sent them a congratulatory message and everyone who took part in making PortaPayments sees them as a honest, worthy winner. In the future I&amp;rsquo;d have no problems in working with them to help them help apps get funded with a tie-up via AndAppStore or help getting the word out to Android developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PayPal X; Where counting is not a requirement and compliance with requirements is optional..</title>
      <link>/post/paypal-counting-not-a-requirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 07:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/paypal-counting-not-a-requirement/</guid>
      <description>If you ran a competition and stated that;
How many entries would you expect to find in the next round?
Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re PayPal, that&amp;rsquo;ll be 11.
And as for &amp;ldquo;gross abuses&amp;rdquo;, well, apparently &amp;ldquo;incentivized voting&amp;rdquo; (i.e. offering rewards for votes) isn&amp;rsquo;t a gross abuse (or certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be enough of a gross abuse to warrant doing anything about), which I&amp;rsquo;m sure is something that any entrant into a voting process would be interested to hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And guess what.... yes, we didn&#39;t make the cut.</title>
      <link>/post/and-guess-what-yes-we-didnt-make-the-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 06:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/and-guess-what-yes-we-didnt-make-the-cut/</guid>
      <description>After all of the problems with seen with the PayPal X Developer Challenge we&amp;rsquo;re hardly surprised that PortaPayments didn&amp;rsquo;t make it through to the next round.
We have, however, asked for details of the per-entry voting count so that we can see if there were any anomalies in the voting patterns (e.g. 1 or 2 entries with &amp;gt; 50% of the votes), and hopefully I will be able to post these details along with details of any of the final 10 which we identified as not complying with the rules in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And on the last day...</title>
      <link>/post/and-on-the-last-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 12:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/and-on-the-last-day/</guid>
      <description>I thought that on the final day of voting it would be worth recapping the &amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo; which has been our listing as a PayPal X Developers Challenge finalist. For us there are statistics which, to us, indicate that something has not been quite right with the way the contest has been run. These are;
  PortaPayments was featured in the PayPal FOWA Presentation.
  PortaPayments wasrecommended in one of the largest on-line Android blogs (Android Guys), and that article was re-tweeted and re-used on other sites.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
