<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Android on </title>
    <link>/tags/Google-Android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Android on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:09:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/Google-Android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Will the Android Market T&amp;Cs kill off &#34;fun&#34; apps?</title>
      <link>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</guid>
      <description>Over recent weeks there has been a lot of speculation over when Android users will be able to buy applications from Googles Market, but some of the terms and conditions in the Developer Distribution Agreement could scare many developers away before they deploy their first application.
The first thing that came to light is that purchasers will have 24 hours in which they can get a refund apparently with no questions asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google finally coming good with the Android Development Programme</title>
      <link>/post/google-finally-coming-good-with-the-android-development-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-finally-coming-good-with-the-android-development-programme/</guid>
      <description>It looks like the folks at Google are listening and they&amp;rsquo;ve taken a big step which will help a number of developers get at least one Android powered device to work with.
Yesterday Dan Morill announced a new version of the SDK with a link to the android blog, what he didn&amp;rsquo;t mention is that the blog post also reveals that Google have created a programme for developers which allows they to get what is basically an unlocked T-Mobile G1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I won&#39;t be buying the Android T-Mobile G1 phone</title>
      <link>/post/why-i-wont-be-buying-the-android-t-mobile-g1-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 09:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-i-wont-be-buying-the-android-t-mobile-g1-phone/</guid>
      <description>After getting interested in Android after Mike Jennings talk, weeks of coding on AndAppStore.com, reading up on APIs, watching and getting involved with discussions on the Android developers and discussion mailing lists, and following various Android community sites to see if the G1 was the start of the Android revolution, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that, for now, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to get an Android &amp;lsquo;phone, and here are the reasons why;
The T-Mobile Deal (phone &amp;amp; contract)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
