<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on </title>
    <link>/categories/Personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:45:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/Personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Twitter</title>
      <link>/post/leaving-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/leaving-twitter/</guid>
      <description>12 days after being told by my EM it could happen, something I&amp;rsquo;ve been expecting to happen for a few weeks has finally happened. Today I was told it is my last day working at Twitter.My EM hadn&amp;rsquo;t been inviting me to strategy meetings, afaik no-one has been offered a job on the team I was supposed to be seeding (apologies to those I referred), and, in my last few weeks, I was tasked with creating dashboards for management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving OUYA</title>
      <link>/post/leaving-ouya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 08:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/leaving-ouya/</guid>
      <description>Nearly 8 months ago I met with a few software engineers working from some rented desks in San Francisco. They were the OUYA engineering team. We talked, they took me through their interview process. I also had a meeting with Julie Uhrman, after which I went from being a believer that it could happen to a believer that it would happen and there was a place on the team for me and I could help make it happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King&#39;s College, London wins ISRI award</title>
      <link>/post/isri-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 1997 11:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isri-award/</guid>
      <description>Al Sutton from King&amp;rsquo;s College, London wins The Internation Systems Research Institute (&amp;ldquo;ISRI&amp;rdquo;) 1997 Award of a top of the range Hewlett-Packard Vectra Pentium 200 worth 3,000 pounds.
Al Sutton, a BSc. in Maths and Computer Science, received his award from Ron McQuaker, President of the British Computer Society at Coutts Bank in London, before an audience of 70 IT Directors and leading IT Academics from Universities from all over the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
