<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>G1 on Al Sutton&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/G1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in G1 on Al Sutton&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 07:50:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/G1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marking Apps on Googles Android Market</title>
      <link>/post/marking-on-the-googles-android-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 07:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/marking-on-the-googles-android-market/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be a lot of variation on how many stars people give an application on Googles Android Market. Some give 3 stars for an app they find hard to use, others give 1 star because the developer chose not to make the applications source code available (even though this doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the application as delivered to the user).
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stick to the following marking scheme and would welcome comments and feedback as to any changes people think would make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Market for Android Paid Apps launch = Fail</title>
      <link>/post/google-market-for-android-paid-apps-launch-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 17:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-market-for-android-paid-apps-launch-fail/</guid>
      <description>Android developers have been waiting for the ability to list pay-for applications in Googles Market, but now most of them wish it had never arrived because the experience it&amp;rsquo;s giving users may just turn them off Android forever.
The first joy is the &amp;ldquo;copy protection&amp;rdquo; offered by Google. Developers can turn this on for their apps but doing so can stop a the application running at all regardless of if it&amp;rsquo;s been copied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will the Android Market T&amp;Cs kill off &#34;fun&#34; apps?</title>
      <link>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/will-the-android-market-tcs-kill-off-fun-apps/</guid>
      <description>Over recent weeks there has been a lot of speculation over when Android users will be able to buy applications from Googles Market, but some of the terms and conditions in the Developer Distribution Agreement could scare many developers away before they deploy their first application.
The first thing that came to light is that purchasers will have 24 hours in which they can get a refund apparently with no questions asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google finally coming good with the Android Development Programme</title>
      <link>/post/google-finally-coming-good-with-the-android-development-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-finally-coming-good-with-the-android-development-programme/</guid>
      <description>It looks like the folks at Google are listening and they&amp;rsquo;ve taken a big step which will help a number of developers get at least one Android powered device to work with.
Yesterday Dan Morill announced a new version of the SDK with a link to the android blog, what he didn&amp;rsquo;t mention is that the blog post also reveals that Google have created a programme for developers which allows they to get what is basically an unlocked T-Mobile G1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Android Email client on the G1, possibly the worst app on an &#34;Internet&#34; phone ever.</title>
      <link>/post/the-android-email-client-on-the-g1-possibly-the-worst-app-on-an-internet-phone-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 12:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-android-email-client-on-the-g1-possibly-the-worst-app-on-an-internet-phone-ever/</guid>
      <description>The G1 has been around a few weeks, it&amp;rsquo;s billed as &amp;ldquo;The phone that&amp;rsquo;s built for the internet&amp;rdquo;, but it would appear that the G1 isn&amp;rsquo;t built for email which many people consider as being one of the most useful things on the internet for over 35 years.
The G1 has two in-built Email clients; one is for Googles&#39; GMail, the other is for accounts with whichever ISP you&amp;rsquo;re with. Personally after seeing several stories of problems with Google locking accounts (see here, here, and here for a few) I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to stay with my ISP, but that leaves me with an Email client which is being described by other G1 users as &amp;ldquo;the most pathetic attempt I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;frustrating&amp;rdquo;, views which I wholeheartedly agree with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
